racks on racks on racks
four things i like about the rep fitness
dumbbell storage rack are the low price
tag the high quality 11 gauge steel the
three tier design offering a small
footprint and you can hold up to a
thousand pounds
[Music]
what's up everyone it's jake back once
again in the barbin garage gym and for
today's review i've got the rep fitness
dumbbell storage rack in this video i'm
going to walk you through everything
this rack has to offer the price some
pros and cons and of course who should
and who should not buy the storage rack
but as always before we get started i
gotta let you know we have reviewed a
good amount of storage racks on
barbind.com to find our best list just
google barbin best storage racks that
article is going to pull right up for
you and you can find out for yourself
which ones we like the best
okay so what do i like about this
dumbbell rack well for starters
it's made with 11 gauge steel which
really nice quality makes it about as
sturdy as it could be oftentimes you'll
find a dumbbell rack of this quality at
a professional gym the three tier design
is really going to cut back on that
floor space without sacrificing ease of
access
and it might not pop out at first glance
but these shelves are actually slightly
angled which makes it even easier to
rack and grab your dumbbells which is a
really nice feature in my opinion
because not all dumbbell racks have that
it only weighs 75 pounds by itself
meaning you can easily move it around
your gym or take it outside if you want
to spend the day lifting outside
plus you can add up to a thousand pounds
on this dumbbell rack
okay so with every single product with
the pros come the cons and that's no
exception here at the storage rack 210
may seem like a value price but once you
consider buying a full set of dumbbells
to be housed on here you're looking at a
pretty expensive purchase
if it falls out of your price range i
would definitely suggest looking for a
cheaper option but on the flip side that
cheaper option most likely will not come
with 11 gauge steel like this one does
a thousand pounds might seem like a lot
of weight some people out there but
there's people out there that lift more
than that so if you're one of those
people i would definitely suggest
finding a storage rack that can hold
over a thousand pounds or maybe even
purchasing two of these racks and it
does have a small footprint but if you
do live in a small area you live in a
small apartment you might not have
enough room for this rack in general
[Music]
priced just over 200 on the rep fitness
website you're getting a pretty awesome
deal for a storage rack that could
essentially last you a lifetime but with
the the addition of a set of dumbbells
you can make this a pretty expensive
purchase
but on the other hand there are dumbbell
racks out there of similar quality
they're gonna cost you around a thousand
dollars so since rep fitness is offering
this rack at a fraction of that price
i think this is a steal
[Music]
with every product i review i like to
talk about the build we're gonna do that
here now this rack was made with 11
gauge steel which is the highest quality
you could ask it to be made of this
three tier design is going to really cut
back on that footprint without
sacrificing utility the shelves are also
the same dimensions meaning you can put
your heavy dumbbells up top on the
bottom it's really just personal
preference and it's only four feet long
about two feet wide and a shade under
three feet tall only weighs 75 pounds
though meaning you can move it around
your home gym by yourself with no
problem or take it outside if you want
to work out outside it's also available
in red blue matte black like we have
here and metallic black
okay so let's dig into some of the
details now with this dumbbell storage
rack
yes it has the three tier design but the
shelves are also the same dimensions
they're 24 inches deep with 42 and a
half inches of usable shelf space plus
there's a one inch lip on each shelf
which is going to allow those dumbbells
to really stay in place when they're
stored and as you can see on this rack
we have here for you today
it has a powder coat on it which really
adds to the aesthetic in my opinion and
it may also add to the durability and
prevent scratches
[Music]
all right guys i'm going to walk you
through this dumbbell storage rack now
starting off it's only 75 pounds meaning
you can easily pick it up and move it
around whenever you need to it's only
four feet long about two feet wide i
wouldn't even say it's three feet tall
doesn't even come up to my waist i
talked about the shelves they all share
the exact same spacing but they also
have this one-inch lip meaning once you
rack a dumbbell
it's in place it's not going anywhere
ours has this nice powder coat
which i personally love
it matches our gym and plus it may even
add to the durability
and prevent scratches and the cherry on
top
look how stable it is
okay so who should buy the rep fitness
dumbbell storage rack well
if you're looking for a rack that's not
going to take up too much space in your
home gym
right here in front of you it's built
with high quality 11 gauge steel which
is the highest quality you could ask for
it to be
it only weighs 75 pounds meaning you can
move it around your gym or take it
outside all by yourself with no problem
and it can still hold up to a thousand
pounds of weight
okay so who shouldn't buy this dumbbell
storage rack well for starters if you
don't have enough space for a set of
dumbbells well then you don't need this
rack
priced around two hundred dollars it
might seem like a really good deal but
once you consider how expensive a set of
dumbbells really are it might fall out
of your price range and if that's the
case i would definitely suggest looking
at a cheaper option but remember those
cheaper options most likely not built
with 11 gauge steel like you'll find
with this dumbbell storage rack
if you need more than a thousand pounds
of dumbbells first of all i'm really
jealous of how strong you are
but you're definitely going to need a
stronger dumbbell storage rack that can
hold up to that much weight or maybe
even consider buying two of these racks
plus if you don't have a set of rep
fitness dumbbells it's not guaranteed
they're gonna fit on this rack so your
best bet really is to just measure
everything out and make sure they're
gonna fit on the available space before
you decide to mix and match
[Music]
that's a wrap on today's review over the
rep fitness dumbbell storage rack this
is a high quality rack available at a
value price
this three tier design you see here it's
gonna cut back on your floor space
meaning you can put it almost anywhere
in your home gym and it only weighs 75
pounds so you can always move it if you
need to most importantly it's made with
11 gauge steel making it as sturdy as it
could be it can hold up to a thousand
pounds of weight for a price tag around
200 dollars it's well worth the money in
my eyes
thanks for watching everybody i hope
this video was really helpful as you
look to find a home for your set of
dumbbells as always head over to
barbin.com you can read more about this
product just search barbin rep fitness
dumbbell storage rack my article is
going to pull up for you and you can
read over everything we discussed here
today i'll see y'all later
[Music]
you